Flora J. Arnstein Papers
Flora J. Arnstein Papers
1930-1964
Arnstein, Flora J.
0.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet, teacher. Born 1885.
Typescript and holograph poems, an article, a booklet, two books, and 18 tearsheets of poems from various journals.
148818
Biographical History
Poet Flora J. Arnstein was born August 10, 1885. She was educated at the University of California and also at the San Francisco State College. She taught poetry, music, and dancing at the elementary-school level for nearly 18 years. Her book Adventure Into Poetry was published in 1951 by Stanford University Press. Poetry in the Elementary Classroom appeared in 1962.
Flora Arnstein's poetry has appeared in the New York Times, London Mercury, Poetry (Chicago), Antioch Review, Accent, Prairie Schooner, and Poetry World.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Flora Arnstein Papers consist of manuscripts and published materials. The Manuscripts section contains typescripts of poems and one holograph poem, all arranged alphabetically by title. The Published material includes her two books, a booklet, a magazine article, and printed copies of poems as they appeared in various journals.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Women Authors; Arnstein, Flora J.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; American poetry -- Women authors.; Women poets, American -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Poems.; Poets.; Teachers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Flora J. Arnstein.
Inventory
- Manuscripts
  - Poems
    - "Autumn", typescript (Box 1)
    - "Beaked Interlude", typescript (Box 1)
    - "Frustration in the Square", holograph (Box 1)
    - "Gulls", typescript (Box 1)
    - "This Ghost", typescript (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Article
    - "Recognizing and Encouraging Creativity in Composition", Elementary English, January 1963 (Box 1)
  - Booklet
    - "Poetry in the Elementary Grades", Primary Reading, no. 14, c.1939 (Box 1)
  - Books
    - Adventure Into Poetry (Box 1)
    - Poetry in the Elementary Classroom (Box 1)
  - Poems
    - "Autumn" PS, no. 2, 1954 (Box 1)
    - "Bequest" Poetry, March 1933 (Box 1)
    - "Communication" Poetry, September 1931 (Box 1)
    - "Emergence" The Midland, January/February 1931 (Box 1)
    - "Exiles" The Humanist, September/October 1959 (Box 1)
    - "Fishes" Poetry, September 1931 (Box 1)
    - "Fullness of Spare" Experiment, Summer 1961 (Box 1)
    - "Gifts" Poetry, September 1931 (Box 1)
    - "Gleaners of Whispers" The Midland, January/February 1931 (Box 1)
    - "Gulls" Accent, Winter 1955 (Box 1)
    - "Interim" The Midland, January/February 1931 (Box 1)
    - "Knowing No Man" Poetry, September 1931 (Box 1)
    - "No Pledges" Poetry, December 1932 (Box 1)
    - "No Winter" Poetry, January 1936 (Box 1)
    - "Only the Dome" Poetry, September 1931 (Box 1)
    - "Plowing Song" Poetry, September 1931 (Box 1)
    - "Sculptor Speaks" The Midland, January/February 1931 (Box 1)
    - "Security" Palms, May 1930 (Box 1)